<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on SNTagore&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://sntag.github.io/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on SNTagore&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sntag.github.io/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidymodels &amp; palmer-penguins</title>
      <link>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-08-04-tidymodels-and-palmers-penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-08-04-tidymodels-and-palmers-penguins/</guid>
      <description>Oddly enough, I’ve been hearing a lot about tidymodels this week, from reddit to youtube. Plus, the tidytuesday dataset this week looks fun.I figure I’ll spend a tidytuesday trying to figure out this new and in-development machine-learning package.
For the newcomer, tidymodels is the planned replacement for the caret package. Complicated machine learning (ml) models will continue using caret for a while as tidymodels is very new to the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Emacs and Julia to work</title>
      <link>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-04-13-getting-emacs-and-julia-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-04-13-getting-emacs-and-julia-to-work/</guid>
      <description>Julia and Emacs Julia is a hot upcoming language. I see nothing but support for it online, and many benchmarks showing a notable improvements over Python or R. The main reason why it is not already rivaling Python or R is the framework and packages. The language is still new, and does not have a mature framework. Even though it is now on the stable v1.4, there are features I&amp;rsquo;ve seen described as as &amp;lsquo;in development&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020: My non-New Years Resolution</title>
      <link>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-01-19-new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sntag.github.io/post/2020-01-19-new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>On 31st Dec, 2019, I was sitting in Kolkata, India, on the lawn of the Kolkata Club.  In front was a stage, musicians and DJs from bollywood.  Around me were relatives and family, ready to celebrate the New Years with a big dinner and lots of musical entertainment.  And for all the excitment around me, it felt like any other New Years. [[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eAFnby2184o][John Oliver]] said it well when he described New Years as &amp;lsquo;/The &lt;em&gt;Worst&lt;/em&gt;!/&#39;.  My track record hasn&amp;rsquo;t been great with New Years.  For all the hype we put on New Year, New Me, we end up falling back into the same habits.  So ironically, I came up with a goal on New Years to spite to all my failed New Years resolution; to write 1-2 scripts a week for a year in any programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>